const hindi = {};

hindi.easy = [
    {
        question: "What is the name of the script used to write Hindi?",
        options: ["Devanagari", "Gurmukhi", "Gujarati", "Bengali"],
        answer: "Devanagari",
    },
    {
        question: "What is the meaning of the word ‘Hindi’?",
        options: [
            "Language of India",
            "Land of Indus River",
            "Sweet and melodious",
            "None of the above",
        ],
        answer: "Land of Indus River",
    },
    {
        question: "When is Hindi Divas celebrated in India?",
        options: [
            "14th September",
            "15th August",
            "26th January",
            "2nd October",
        ],
        answer: "14th September",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these languages is not a dialect of Hindi?",
        options: ["Bhojpuri", "Maithili", "Marathi", "Awadhi"],
        answer: "Marathi",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these countries has Hindi as an official language?",
        options: ["Fiji", "Nepal", "Pakistan", "Bangladesh"],
        answer: "Fiji",
    },
    {
        question:
            "Which of these words is not borrowed from Sanskrit in Hindi?",
        options: ["Guru", "Karma", "Pyjama", "Yoga"],
        answer: "Pyjama",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is the Hindi name for the number zero?",
        options: ["Shunya", "Ek", "Das", "Sifar"],
        answer: "Shunya",
    },
    {
        question:
            "Which of these words is the Hindi name for the national emblem of India?",
        options: [
            "Ashoka Chakra",
            "Bharat Mata",
            "Sarnath Lion Capital",
            "Tricolour Flag",
        ],
        answer: "Sarnath Lion Capital",
    },
    {
        question:
            "Which of these words is the Hindi name for the national bird of India?",
        options: ["Mor", "Hamsa", "Garuda", "Mayur"],
        answer: "Mor",
    },
    {
        question:
            "Which of these words is the Hindi name for the national anthem of India?",
        options: [
            "Vande Mataram",
            "Jana Gana Mana",
            "Sare Jahan Se Achha",
            "Raghupati Raghav Raja Ram",
        ],
        answer: "Jana Gana Mana",
    },
];
hindi.medium = [
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a synonym of ‘अभिनव’ in Hindi?",
        options: ["नवीन", "अभिशाप", "अभिमान", "अभियान"],
        answer: "नवीन",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is an antonym of ‘उदास’ in Hindi?",
        options: ["खुश", "दुखी", "चिंतित", "निराश"],
        answer: "खुश",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a feminine noun in Hindi?",
        options: ["बालक", "बालिका", "बाघ", "बादल"],
        answer: "बालिका",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a masculine noun in Hindi?",
        options: ["फूल", "घर", "आदमी", "नदी"],
        answer: "आदमी",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a singular noun in Hindi?",
        options: ["बच्चे", "बच्चा", "बच्चों", "बच्चाओं"],
        answer: "बच्चा",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a plural noun in Hindi?",
        options: [
            "किताब",
            "किताबें",
            "किताबों",
            "किताबें और किताबों",
        ],
        answer: "किताबें और किताबों",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a verb in Hindi?",
        options: ["गाना", "गाने", "गाता", "गायक"],
        answer: "गाता",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is an adjective in Hindi?",
        options: ["लड़का", "लड़की", "लड़के", "लड़का-लड़की"],
        answer: "लड़का-लड़की",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a pronoun in Hindi?",
        options: ["मैं", "मेरा", "मुझे", "मुझसे"],
        answer: "मैं",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a conjunction in Hindi?",
        options: ["और", "या", "लेकिन", "सभी"],
        answer: "सभी",
    },
];
hindi.hard = [
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a palindrome in Hindi?",
        options: ["नितिन", "राम", "अजय", "अमित"],
        answer: "नितिन",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a homonym in Hindi?",
        options: ["बाल", "बाला", "बाली", "बालू"],
        answer: "बाल",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a compound word in Hindi?",
        options: ["राजधानी", "राजकुमारी", "राजकुमार", "राजपूत"],
        answer: "राजधानी",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a tatsam word in Hindi?",
        options: ["आँख", "नेत्र", "चश्मा", "दृष्टि"],
        answer: "नेत्र",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a tadbhav word in Hindi?",
        options: ["विद्या", "शिक्षा", "पढ़ाई", "ज्ञान"],
        answer: "पढ़ाई",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a deshaj word in Hindi?",
        options: ["गाड़ी", "रेल", "ट्रेन", "लोकोमोटिव"],
        answer: "गाड़ी",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a videshi word in Hindi?",
        options: ["टमाटर", "आलू", "गोभी", "बैगन"],
        answer: "टमाटर",
    },
    {
        question:
            "Which of these words is a sandhi vichhed of ‘अधिकारी’ in Hindi?",
        options: [
            "अधि + कारी",
            "अधि + क + आरी",
            "अ + धि + कारी",
            "अ + धि + क + आरी",
        ],
        answer: "अधि + क + आरी",
    },
    {
        question:
            "Which of these words is a samasik word of ‘देवदत्त’ in Hindi?",
        options: [
            "देव + दत्त",
            "देव + दत्ता",
            "देव + दत्तानंद",
            "देव + दत्ताराम",
        ],
        answer: "देव + दत्त",
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these words is a pratyay of ‘विद्यालय’ in Hindi?",
        options: ["विद्या", "विद्याल", "लय", "आलय"],
        answer: "आलय",
    },
];

module.exports = hindi;
